<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' standalone='no'?>
<section xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" version="5.0" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xml:id="_md__o_1__git_h_u_b_m_i_n_i_p_roject__library__package_cache_com_8unity_8package-manager-ui_0D2_80_87__documentation">

<para>A package is a container that holds any combination of Assets, Shaders, Textures, plug-ins, icons, and scripts that enhance various parts of your Project, including Unity modules (such as Physics or Animation). Unity packages are newer, more tightly integrated versions of Asset Store packages, able to deliver a wide range of enhancements to Unity.</para>

<para>Use the Unity Package Manager (in Unity’s top menu: <emphasis role="bold">Window</emphasis> &gt; <emphasis role="bold">Package Manager</emphasis>) to view which packages are available for installation or already installed in your Project. In addition, you can use this window to see <link xlink:href="#VersionList">which versions are available</link>, and <link xlink:href="#PackManInstall">install</link>, <link xlink:href="#PackManRemove">remove</link>, <link xlink:href="#PackManDisable">disable</link>, or <link xlink:href="#PackManUpdate">update</link> packages for each Project.</para>

<para></para>

<para>The Packages window displays:</para>

<para><itemizedlist>
<listitem>
<para>(A) The <link xlink:href="#scope">package scope drop-down menu</link>, which allows you to filter which packages appear in the list.</para>
</listitem><listitem>
<para>(B) The <link xlink:href="#advanced">Advanced button</link>, which allows you to display preview packages in addition to packages that have been verified to work with Unity.</para>
</listitem><listitem>
<para>(C) The <link xlink:href="#searchText">search box</link>, which allows you to look for packages by name.</para>
</listitem><listitem>
<para>(D) The <link xlink:href="#PackManLists">packages list view</link>, which displays all packages that match the filter and search parameters you specify.</para>
</listitem><listitem>
<para>(E) The <link xlink:href="#PackManDetails">package-specific detail view</link>, which displays information specific to the package selected in the list.</para>
</listitem><listitem>
<para>(F) The <link xlink:href="#statusbar">status bar</link>, which displays messages about the package load status and warnings about the network.</para>
</listitem><listitem>
<para>(G) The <link xlink:href="#extpkg">Add package from disk button</link>, which allows you to specify the location of an external package.</para>
</listitem></itemizedlist>
</para>

<para><anchor xml:id="__1PackManLists"/> <formalpara><title>Finding packages</title></formalpara>
</para>

<para>The Packages window displays the following types of Unity packages:</para>

<para><itemizedlist>
<listitem>
<para><emphasis role="bold">Read-only packages</emphasis></para>

<para>These are packages which the Package Manager downloads from the <link xlink:href="#PackManRegistry">Unity package registry</link> as needed. They are not bundled with the Project source and may have dependencies on other packages in external Projects. This type is typical of most Unity packages.</para>
</listitem><listitem>
<para><emphasis role="bold">Local packages</emphasis></para>

<para>These are packages that you saved on your computer in an <link xlink:href="#extpkg">external</link> location outside of your current Unity Project.</para>
</listitem><listitem>
<para><emphasis role="bold">Built-in packages</emphasis></para>

<para>These represent some of the core Unity features. You can use these packages to <link xlink:href="#PackManDisable">turn Unity modules on and off</link>.</para>
</listitem></itemizedlist>
</para>

<para><emphasis role="bold">Note</emphasis>: You can find out more about what each module implements in the <link xlink:href="https://docs.unity3d.com/ScriptReference/">Unity Scripting API</link>. Each module assembly page lists which APIs the built-in package implements.</para>

<para>By default, the Packages window displays the list of all packages either registered in the <link xlink:href="#PackManRegistry">package registry</link> or installed <link xlink:href="#extpkg">locally</link>.</para>

<para>The following icons show you package status:</para>

<para> A check mark indicates that the package is already <link xlink:href="#PackManInstall">installed</link> or <link xlink:href="#PackManDisable">enabled</link>.</para>

<para> The download icon indicates that the installed packages has <link xlink:href="#PackManUpdate">an available update</link>.</para>

<para> An error icon indicates that something went wrong during installation or loading. For more advice on resolving errors, see <link xlink:href="#troubleshooting">Error messages</link> below.</para>

<para>You can <link xlink:href="#scope">filter</link> the list to display only packages installed in your Project (including <link xlink:href="#extpkg">local</link> packages), or display only built-in Unity packages. You can also <link xlink:href="#searchText">search</link> for a specific package by package name, tag, or package version number.</para>

<para><anchor xml:id="__1scope"/> <formalpara><title>Filtering the list</title></formalpara>
</para>

<para>To change which packages appear in the list, select the scope you want from the drop-down menu in the left hand corner of the Packages window.</para>

<para>You can select from these options:</para>

<para><itemizedlist>
<listitem>
<para>The <emphasis role="bold">All packages</emphasis> scope (the default) displays all packages on the <link xlink:href="#PackManRegistry">package registry</link>, regardless of whether they are already installed in your Project. This also includes <link xlink:href="#extpkg">local</link> packages (which are always installed).</para>
</listitem><listitem>
<para>The <emphasis role="bold">In Project</emphasis> scope displays all packages currently installed in your Project, including <link xlink:href="#extpkg">local</link> packages.</para>
</listitem><listitem>
<para>The <emphasis role="bold">Built-in packages</emphasis> scope displays only built-in Unity packages.</para>
</listitem></itemizedlist>
</para>

<para>When you select a new scope, your choice appears on the package scope drop-down menu and the list displays the packages matching your choice.</para>

<para><emphasis role="bold">Note:</emphasis> If you entered any text in the <link xlink:href="#searchText">search box</link>, the list only displays packages which match both the scope and the search criteria.</para>

<para><anchor xml:id="__1advanced"/> <formalpara><title>Advanced button</title></formalpara>
</para>

<para>The <emphasis role="bold">Advanced</emphasis> button opens a drop-down menu that allows you to show preview packages. Preview package are not verified to work with Unity and might be unstable. They are not not supported in production environments.</para>

<para>To show the preview packages that are available, click the <emphasis role="bold">Advanced</emphasis> button, then click the <emphasis role="bold">Show preview packages</emphasis> menu item.</para>

<para><anchor xml:id="__1searchText"/> <formalpara><title>Searching for packages</title></formalpara>
</para>

<para>You can use the search box at the top of the Packages window to find any packages that match the text you enter. The Package Manager updates the package list as you enter text, displaying every package within the current scope that matches. For example, if you enter <computeroutput>web</computeroutput> in the search box, the list displays different results depending on whether you chose the <emphasis role="bold">Built-in packages</emphasis> scope or the <emphasis role="bold">All packages</emphasis> scope:</para>

<para></para>

<para>You can look for a package by its <link xlink:href="#PackManManifestsPackage">package name</link>, its <link xlink:href="#version_tags">tag name</link>, or its <link xlink:href="#VersionList">package version number</link>. The Package Manager analyzes the text that you enter to detect which method you are using and updates the list of packages dynamically.</para>

<para><emphasis role="bold">Package name</emphasis></para>

<para>You can search for either the display name as it appears in the Packages window, or the registered package name that begins with <computeroutput>com.unity</computeroutput>.</para>

<para>Your search text could match the beginning, middle, or end of the package&apos;s name.</para>

<para><emphasis role="bold">Tag name</emphasis></para>

<para>To search by tag name, enter one of the package version tags. For example, if you enter <computeroutput>verified</computeroutput> in the search box, only packages with a verified tag appear, regardless of their package name.</para>

<para><emphasis role="bold">Version number</emphasis></para>

<para>Enter the <link xlink:href="#VersionList">version number</link> in version order (<computeroutput>MAJOR.MINOR.PATCH</computeroutput>). For example, typing <computeroutput>1</computeroutput> returns all packages with versions matching <computeroutput>1.x.x</computeroutput> (for example, <computeroutput>1.0.0</computeroutput>, <computeroutput>1.3.2</computeroutput>, and <computeroutput>1.10.1</computeroutput> all match but not <computeroutput>0.1.0</computeroutput> ).</para>

<para><anchor xml:id="__1statusbar"/> <formalpara><title>Status bar</title></formalpara>
</para>

<para>The Package Manager displays messages in the status bar at the bottom left of the Packages window.</para>

<para>There are typically three status messages that you might see. The <emphasis role="bold">Loading packages</emphasis> message appears briefly the first time you open Packman UI in a new Project. However, if the Package Manager <link xlink:href="#troubleshooting">detects a problem</link>, such as a missing network connection, the Package Manager displays a warning in the status bar:</para>

<para></para>

<para>You will also often see a message informing you when the last update occurred:</para>

<para></para>

<para><anchor xml:id="__1PackManDetails"/> <formalpara><title>Viewing package details</title></formalpara>
</para>

<para>The pane on the right side of the Packages window displays details about the selected package.</para>

<para></para>

<para>These details include the following information:<itemizedlist>
<listitem>
<para>(A) The display name</para>
</listitem><listitem>
<para>(B) The <link xlink:href="#VersionList">version number</link> (and <link xlink:href="#version_tags">tag</link>, if available)</para>
</listitem><listitem>
<para>(C) The <link xlink:href="#links">links</link> to open the package documentation page, the package change log (if available), and the license information.</para>
</listitem><listitem>
<para>(D) The official package name from the <link xlink:href="#PackManRegistry">registry</link> starting with <computeroutput>com.unity.</computeroutput></para>
</listitem><listitem>
<para>(E) The author</para>
</listitem><listitem>
<para>(F) A brief description</para>
</listitem><listitem>
<para>(G) Buttons to <link xlink:href="#PackManInstall">install</link> or <link xlink:href="#PackManUpdate">update</link> a package (or the <emphasis role="bold">Up to date</emphasis> message if the selected version is already installed)</para>
</listitem><listitem>
<para>(H) The package version drop-down menu</para>
</listitem><listitem>
<para>(I) Buttons to <link xlink:href="#PackManRemove">remove</link> or <link xlink:href="#PackManDisable">disable</link> the package</para>
</listitem></itemizedlist>
</para>

<para><anchor xml:id="__1VersionList"/> <formalpara><title>List of versions</title></formalpara>
</para>

<para>You can view the list of versions available for the current package by clicking the version drop-down menu beside the <emphasis role="bold">Update to</emphasis> or <emphasis role="bold">Install</emphasis> button in the upper right of the Package specific detail view.</para>

<para><itemizedlist>
<listitem>
<para>(A) The main menu displays the current version, the latest version (even if it is a preview), and the verified version.</para>
</listitem><listitem>
<para>(B) The submenu displays all available versions.</para>
</listitem></itemizedlist>
</para>

<para>You can select any of these versions for the current package and install that specific version using the <emphasis role="bold">Install</emphasis> or <emphasis role="bold">Update to</emphasis> button.</para>

<para><anchor xml:id="__1version_tags"/> <formalpara><title>Version tags</title></formalpara>
</para>

<para>Some packages display tags next to the version number. These tags convey information about that version of the package.</para>

<para>The Package Manager uses the following values:</para>

<para><informaltable frame="all">
    <tgroup cols="2" align="left" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
      <colspec colname='c1'/>
      <colspec colname='c2'/>
<thead>
      <row >
<entry>
<para><emphasis role="bold">Tag</emphasis>  </para>
</entry><entry>
<para><emphasis role="bold">Meaning</emphasis>   </para>
</entry></row>
</thead><tbody>
      <row >
<entry>
<para><computeroutput>Verified</computeroutput>  </para>
</entry><entry>
<para>This package has been verified by Unity&apos;s Quality Assurance team to work with a specific version of the Editor.   </para>
</entry></row>
      <row >
<entry>
<para><computeroutput>Preview</computeroutput>  </para>
</entry><entry>
<para>This package is at an early stage of the release cycle and may not have been documented and fully validated by either the development team or Unity&apos;s Quality Assurance team.   </para>
</entry></row>
      <row >
<entry>
<para><computeroutput>Local</computeroutput>  </para>
</entry><entry>
<para>This package is located on your local disk but is external to your Unity Project folder.   </para>
</entry></row>
      <row >
<entry>
<para>*(no tag)*  </para>
</entry><entry>
<para>This package is considered production quality, which means it is fully validated, documented, supported, and incrementally updated.   </para>
</entry></row>
    </tbody>
    </tgroup>
</informaltable>
</para>

<para><anchor xml:id="__1links"/> <formalpara><title>Finding more information</title></formalpara>
</para>

<para>You can find out more about a package by viewing its documentation, changelog, or license information.</para>

<para>To access any of these pages, click the <emphasis role="bold">View documentation</emphasis>, <emphasis role="bold">View changelog</emphasis>, or <emphasis role="bold">View licences</emphasis> links.</para>

<para>The package page opens in your default browser.</para>

<para></para>

<para>To switch back and forth between the <emphasis>Manual</emphasis> documentation, the <emphasis>Scripting API</emphasis> documentation, the <emphasis>Changelog</emphasis>, and the <emphasis>License</emphasis> information for this package, click the corresponding link at the top of the page.</para>

<para><anchor xml:id="__1PackManOpen"/> <formalpara><title>Installing, removing, disabling, and updating packages</title></formalpara>
</para>

<para>You can perform a variety of tasks through the Packages window:</para>

<para><itemizedlist>
<listitem>
<para><link xlink:href="#PackManInstall">Install a new package</link></para>
</listitem><listitem>
<para><link xlink:href="#PackManRemove">Remove an installed package</link></para>
</listitem><listitem>
<para><link xlink:href="#PackManDisable">Disable a built-in package</link></para>
</listitem><listitem>
<para><link xlink:href="#PackManUpdate">Update an installed package</link></para>
</listitem><listitem>
<para><link xlink:href="#extpkg">Specify an external package location</link></para>
</listitem></itemizedlist>
</para>

<para><formalpara><title>Accessing the Packages window</title></formalpara>
</para>

<para>To open the Packages window, navigate to Unity&apos;s main menu and go to <emphasis role="bold">Window</emphasis> &gt; <emphasis role="bold">Package Manager</emphasis>.</para>

<para><anchor xml:id="__1PackManInstall"/> <formalpara><title>Installing a new package</title></formalpara>
</para>

<para>To install a new package:</para>

<para><orderedlist>
<listitem>
<para>Open the Packages window and select <emphasis role="bold">All packages</emphasis> from the <link xlink:href="#scope">package scope</link> drop-down menu.</para>
</listitem><listitem>
<para>Select the package you want to install from the <link xlink:href="#PackManLists">list of packages</link>. The package information appears in the <link xlink:href="#PackManDetails">details pane</link>.</para>
</listitem><listitem>
<para>Select the version you want from the <link xlink:href="#VersionList">version drop-down menu</link>.</para>
</listitem><listitem>
<para>Click the <emphasis role="bold">Install</emphasis> button. When the progress bar finishes, the new package is ready to use.</para>
</listitem></orderedlist>
</para>

<para><anchor xml:id="__1PackManRemove"/> <formalpara><title>Removing an installed package</title></formalpara>
</para>

<para>You can only remove packages which are not required by another package.</para>

<para>When you remove a package, any Editor or run-time functionality which it implemented is no longer available.</para>

<para>To remove an installed package:</para>

<para><orderedlist>
<listitem>
<para>Open the Packages window and select <emphasis role="bold">In Project</emphasis> (or <emphasis role="bold">All packages</emphasis>) from the <link xlink:href="#scope">package scope</link> drop-down menu.</para>
</listitem><listitem>
<para>Select the package you want to remove from the <link xlink:href="#PackManLists">list of packages</link>. The package information appears in the <link xlink:href="#PackManDetails">details pane</link>.</para>
</listitem><listitem>
<para>Click the <emphasis role="bold">Remove</emphasis> button. When the progress bar finishes, the package disappears from the list.</para>
</listitem></orderedlist>
</para>

<para>You can restore a removed package from the list when you are in the <emphasis role="bold">All packages</emphasis> scope.</para>

<para><anchor xml:id="__1PackManDisable"/> <formalpara><title>Disabling a built-in package</title></formalpara>
</para>

<para>You can disable a built-in package if you don&apos;t need some modules and you want to save resources. However, when you disable a built-in package, the corresponding Unity functionality is no longer available. This results in the following:</para>

<para><itemizedlist>
<listitem>
<para>If you use a Scripting API implemented by a disabled package, you get compiler errors.</para>
</listitem><listitem>
<para>Components implemented by the disabled built-in package are also disabled, which means you cannot add them to any GameObjects. If you have a GameObject that already has one of these components, Unity ignores them in Play mode. You can see them in the Inspector window but they are greyed out to indicate that they are not available.</para>
</listitem><listitem>
<para>When building a game, Unity strips all disabled components. For build targets which support engine code stripping (like WebGL, iOS, and Android), Unity doesn&apos;t add any code from a disabled built-in package.</para>
</listitem></itemizedlist>
</para>

<para>To disable a built-in package:<orderedlist>
<listitem>
<para>Open the Packages window and select <emphasis role="bold">Built-in packages</emphasis> from the <link xlink:href="#scope">package scope</link> drop-down menu.</para>
</listitem><listitem>
<para>Select the package you want to remove from the <link xlink:href="#PackManLists">list of packages</link>. Its information appears in the Details pane.</para>
</listitem><listitem>
<para>Click the <emphasis role="bold">Disable</emphasis> button. When the progress bar finishes, the check mark no longer appears next to the built-in package and the <emphasis role="bold">Disable</emphasis> button becomes an <emphasis role="bold">Enable</emphasis> button.</para>
</listitem></orderedlist>
</para>

<para>To re-enable a disabled built-in package, click the <emphasis role="bold">Enable</emphasis> button.</para>

<para><anchor xml:id="__1PackManUpdate"/> <formalpara><title>Updating an installed package</title></formalpara>
</para>

<para>You can update a package while in either the <emphasis role="bold">In Project</emphasis> or <emphasis role="bold">All</emphasis> mode:</para>

<para><orderedlist>
<listitem>
<para>Open the Packages window. An arrow indicator appears next to any packages that have updates available.</para>
</listitem><listitem>
<para>Select the package you want to update from the <link xlink:href="#PackManLists">list of packages</link>. The package information appears in the <link xlink:href="#PackManDetails">details pane</link>.</para>
</listitem><listitem>
<para>Select the version you want from the <link xlink:href="#VersionList">version drop-down menu</link>.</para>
</listitem><listitem>
<para>Click the <emphasis role="bold">Update to</emphasis> button.</para>
</listitem></orderedlist>
</para>

<para>When the progress bar finishes, the new package version information appears in the Details pane, and any new functionality is immediately available.</para>

<para><anchor xml:id="__1extpkg"/> <formalpara><title>Specifying a local package location</title></formalpara>
</para>

<para>The Package Manager can load a package from anywhere on your computer even if you saved it outside your Unity Project folder. For example, if you have a package called <computeroutput>com.unity.my-local-package</computeroutput> and you save it on the <computeroutput>Desktop</computeroutput> but your Unity Project is under the <computeroutput>Documents</computeroutput> folder.</para>

<para>To load a package from your local disk:</para>

<para><orderedlist>
<listitem>
<para>Click the plus (<computeroutput>+</computeroutput>) icon in the status bar.</para>

<para>The <emphasis role="bold">Add package from disk</emphasis> button appears.</para>

<para></para>
</listitem><listitem>
<para>Click the <emphasis role="bold">Add package from disk</emphasis> button to bring up a file browser.</para>
</listitem><listitem>
<para>Navigate to the folder root of your local package.</para>
</listitem><listitem>
<para>Double-click the <computeroutput>package.json</computeroutput> file in the file browser.</para>

<para>The file browser closes and the package now appears in the <link xlink:href="#PackManLists">package list</link> with the <computeroutput>local</computeroutput> tag.</para>
</listitem></orderedlist>
</para>

<para><anchor xml:id="__1troubleshooting"/> <formalpara><title>Error messages</title></formalpara>
</para>

<para>The Package Manager displays error indicators when it encounters problems:</para>

<para><itemizedlist>
<listitem>
<para><emphasis role="bold">System-wide issues</emphasis></para>

<para>Error messages that appear in the <link xlink:href="#statusbar">status bar</link> indicate the Package Manager has detected an issue that is not related to a specific package. For example, if the Package Manager cannot access the <link xlink:href="#PackManRegistry">package registry server</link>, it displays this message in the status bar:</para>

<para></para>

<para>If your network cannot reach the package registry server, it is probably because there is a connection problem with the network. When you or your system administrator fix the network error, the status bar clears.</para>
</listitem><listitem>
<para><emphasis role="bold">Package-specific issues</emphasis></para>

<para>If a specific package has a problem when loading or installing, the error icon () appears in the <link xlink:href="#PackManLists">package list</link> next to the compromised package. To find out what the problem is, open the compromised package&apos;s <link xlink:href="#PackManDetails">details pane</link>.</para>
</listitem></itemizedlist>
</para>

<para><formalpara><title>Understanding how packages work</title></formalpara>
</para>

<para>In addition to its contents (Assets, Shaders, Textures, plug-ins, icons, and scripts), a Unity package contains a <link xlink:href="#PackManManifestsPackage">package manifest file</link>. The package manifest tells Unity how to display its information page in the Packages window, and how to install the package in the Project.</para>

<para>It also contains several files that help manage package deployment, including the tests, samples, license, changelog, and documentation.</para>

<para><anchor xml:id="__1PackManManifests"/> <formalpara><title>Manifests</title></formalpara>
</para>

<para>There are two types of manifest files: <link xlink:href="#PackManManifestsProject">Project</link> manifests (<computeroutput>manifest.json</computeroutput>), and <link xlink:href="#PackManManifestsPackage">package</link> manifests (<computeroutput>package.json</computeroutput>). Both files use JSON (JavaScript Object Notation) syntax to communicate with the Package Manager, by describing which packages are available for each Project, and what each package contains.</para>

<para><anchor xml:id="__1PackManManifestsProject"/> <formalpara><title>Project manifests</title></formalpara>
</para>

<para>Project manifests (<computeroutput>manifest.json</computeroutput>) tell the Package Manager which packages and versions are available to the Project.</para>

<para>Project manifests support the following value:</para>

<para><informaltable frame="all">
    <tgroup cols="3" align="left" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
      <colspec colname='c1'/>
      <colspec colname='c2'/>
      <colspec colname='c3'/>
<thead>
      <row >
<entry>
<para>Key  </para>
</entry><entry>
<para>JSON Type  </para>
</entry><entry>
<para>Description   </para>
</entry></row>
</thead><tbody>
      <row >
<entry>
<para><computeroutput>dependencies</computeroutput>  </para>
</entry><entry>
<para>Object  </para>
</entry><entry>
<para>List of packages for the Package Manager to load. These are usually packages officially registered with Unity, but may also include <link xlink:href="#extpkg">local packages that are external</link> to your Unity project.   </para>
</entry></row>
    </tbody>
    </tgroup>
</informaltable>
</para>

<para>Example of a <computeroutput>manifest.json</computeroutput> file: <literallayout><computeroutput>{
    &quot;dependencies&quot;: {
        &quot;com.unity.package-1&quot;: &quot;1.0.0&quot;,
        &quot;com.unity.package-2&quot;: &quot;2.0.0&quot;,
        &quot;com.unity.package-3&quot;: &quot;3.0.0&quot;,
        &quot;com.unity.my-local-package&quot;: &quot;file:/&lt;external_path&gt;/com.unity.my-local-package&quot;
    }
}
</computeroutput></literallayout></para>

<para>Unity stores each Project manifest in the <computeroutput>[your_Project_root_folder]/Packages/manifest.json</computeroutput> file.</para>

<para><anchor xml:id="__1PackManManifestsPackage"/> <formalpara><title>Package manifests</title></formalpara>
</para>

<para>The Package Manager uses package manifests (<computeroutput>package.json</computeroutput>) to determine which version of the package to load, and what information to display in the Packages window.</para>

<para>Package manifests support the following values:</para>

<para><informaltable frame="all">
    <tgroup cols="3" align="left" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
      <colspec colname='c1'/>
      <colspec colname='c2'/>
      <colspec colname='c3'/>
<thead>
      <row >
<entry>
<para>Key  </para>
</entry><entry>
<para>JSON Type  </para>
</entry><entry>
<para>Description   </para>
</entry></row>
</thead><tbody>
      <row >
<entry>
<para><computeroutput>name</computeroutput>  </para>
</entry><entry>
<para>String  </para>
</entry><entry>
<para>The officially registered package name, following this naming convention: <computeroutput>&quot;com.unity.[package name]&quot;</computeroutput>. For example, <computeroutput>&quot;com.unity.resourcemanager&quot;</computeroutput>   </para>
</entry></row>
      <row >
<entry>
<para><computeroutput>displayName</computeroutput>  </para>
</entry><entry>
<para>String  </para>
</entry><entry>
<para>The package name as it appears in the Packages window. For example, <computeroutput>&quot;Resource Manager&quot;</computeroutput>   </para>
</entry></row>
      <row >
<entry>
<para><computeroutput>version</computeroutput>  </para>
</entry><entry>
<para>String  </para>
</entry><entry>
<para>The package version <computeroutput>&quot;MAJOR.MINOR.PATCH&quot;</computeroutput>. Unity packages follow the <link xlink:href="https://semver.org">Semantic Versioning</link> system. For example, <computeroutput>&quot;1.3.0&quot;</computeroutput>.   </para>
</entry></row>
      <row >
<entry>
<para><computeroutput>unity</computeroutput>  </para>
</entry><entry>
<para>String  </para>
</entry><entry>
<para>The Unity version that supports this package. For example, <computeroutput>&quot;2018.1&quot;</computeroutput> indicates compatibility starting with Unity version 2018.1.   </para>
</entry></row>
      <row >
<entry>
<para><computeroutput>description</computeroutput>  </para>
</entry><entry>
<para>String  </para>
</entry><entry>
<para>A brief description of the package. This is the text that appears on the Details pane of the Packages window. Some special formatting character codes are supported, such as line breaks (<computeroutput>\n</computeroutput>) and bullets (<computeroutput>\u25AA</computeroutput>).   </para>
</entry></row>
      <row >
<entry>
<para><computeroutput>category</computeroutput>  </para>
</entry><entry>
<para>String  </para>
</entry><entry>
<para>The category this packages is in. For example, <computeroutput>&quot;Forces&quot;</computeroutput>.   </para>
</entry></row>
      <row >
<entry>
<para><computeroutput>dependencies</computeroutput>  </para>
</entry><entry>
<para>Object  </para>
</entry><entry>
<para>A list of packages that this package depends on, expressed as a JSON dictionary where the key is the package name and the value is the version number. Unity downloads all dependencies and loads them into the project alongside this package.   </para>
</entry></row>
    </tbody>
    </tgroup>
</informaltable>
</para>

<para>Example of a <computeroutput>package.json</computeroutput> file: <literallayout><computeroutput>{
    &quot;name&quot;: &quot;com.unity.package-4&quot;,
    &quot;displayName&quot;: &quot;Package Number 4&quot;,
    &quot;version&quot;: &quot;2.5.1&quot;,
    &quot;unity&quot;: &quot;2018.2&quot;,
    &quot;description&quot;: &quot;This package provides X, Y, and Z. \n\nTo find out more, click the \&quot;View documentation\&quot; link.&quot;,
    &quot;keywords&quot;: [&quot;key X&quot;, &quot;key Y&quot;, &quot;key Z&quot;],
    &quot;category&quot;: &quot;Controllers&quot;,
    &quot;dependencies&quot;: {
        &quot;com.unity.package-1&quot;: &quot;1.0.0&quot;,
        &quot;com.unity.package-2&quot;: &quot;2.0.0&quot;,
        &quot;com.unity.package-3&quot;: &quot;3.0.0&quot;
    }
}
</computeroutput></literallayout></para>

<para>Unity stores each package manifest in the <computeroutput>[package_root_folder]/package.json</computeroutput> file.</para>

<para><anchor xml:id="__1PackManRegistry"/> <formalpara><title>Package registry</title></formalpara>
</para>

<para>Unity maintains a central registry of official packages that are available for distribution. When Unity loads, the Package Manager communicates with the registry, checks the Project manifest file, and displays the status of each available package in the Packages window.</para>

<para>When you remove a package from the Project, the Package Manager updates the Project manifest to exclude that package from the list when in <emphasis role="bold">In Project</emphasis> mode but it is still available in <emphasis role="bold">All packages</emphasis> mode because it is still in the registry.</para>

<para>When you install or update a package, the Package Manager downloads the package from the registry.</para>

<para><formalpara><title>Technical details</title></formalpara>
</para>

<para><formalpara><title>Requirements</title></formalpara>
</para>

<para>This version of Unity Package Manager is compatible with the following versions of the Unity Editor:</para>

<para><itemizedlist>
<listitem>
<para>2018.3 and later (recommended)</para>
</listitem></itemizedlist>
</para>

<para><formalpara><title>Documentation revision history</title></formalpara>
</para>

<para><informaltable frame="all">
    <tgroup cols="2" align="left" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
      <colspec colname='c1'/>
      <colspec colname='c2'/>
<thead>
      <row >
<entry>
<para>Date  </para>
</entry><entry>
<para>Reason   </para>
</entry></row>
</thead><tbody>
      <row >
<entry>
<para>October 3, 2018  </para>
</entry><entry>
<para>Documentation updated. Image updates and minor corrections.   </para>
</entry></row>
      <row >
<entry>
<para>September 14, 2018  </para>
</entry><entry>
<para>Documentation updated. Matches package version 2.0.1.   </para>
</entry></row>
      <row >
<entry>
<para>June 4, 2018  </para>
</entry><entry>
<para>Documentation updated. Matches package version 2.0.0.   </para>
</entry></row>
      <row >
<entry>
<para>May 25, 2018  </para>
</entry><entry>
<para>Documentation updated. Matches package version 1.9.9.   </para>
</entry></row>
      <row >
<entry>
<para>May 4, 2018  </para>
</entry><entry>
<para>Documentation updated. Matches package version 1.9.8.   </para>
</entry></row>
      <row >
<entry>
<para>March 19, 2018  </para>
</entry><entry>
<para>Documentation updated. Matches package version 1.9.0.   </para>
</entry></row>
      <row >
<entry>
<para>Feb 8, 2018  </para>
</entry><entry>
<para>Documentation updated. Matches package version 1.7.0.   </para>
</entry></row>
      <row >
<entry>
<para>Feb 6, 2018  </para>
</entry><entry>
<para>Documentation cleaned up. Matches package version 1.6.1.   </para>
</entry></row>
      <row >
<entry>
<para>Jan 31, 2018  </para>
</entry><entry>
<para>Documentation updated (developmental review)   </para>
</entry></row>
      <row >
<entry>
<para>Jan 29, 2018  </para>
</entry><entry>
<para>Document updated. Matches package version 1.6.0.   </para>
</entry></row>
      <row >
<entry>
<para>Jan 18, 2018  </para>
</entry><entry>
<para>Document updated. Matches package version 1.5.1.   </para>
</entry></row>
      <row >
<entry>
<para>Jan 17, 2018  </para>
</entry><entry>
<para>Document updated. Matches package version 1.5.0.   </para>
</entry></row>
      <row >
<entry>
<para>Jan 12, 2018  </para>
</entry><entry>
<para>Document updated. Matches package version 1.4.0.   </para>
</entry></row>
      <row >
<entry>
<para>Nov 7, 2017  </para>
</entry><entry>
<para>Document created. Matches package version 1.0.0.   </para>
</entry></row>
    </tbody>
    </tgroup>
</informaltable>
</para>
</section>
