<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' standalone='no'?>
<doxygen xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="compound.xsd" version="1.8.15">
  <compounddef id="md__o_1__git_h_u_b_m_i_n_i_p_roject__library__package_cache_com_8unity_8textmeshpro_0D1_83_80__documentation__text_mesh_pro" kind="page">
    <compoundname>md_O:_GitHUBMINIPRoject_Library_PackageCache_com.unity.textmeshpro@1.3.0_Documentation_TextMeshPro</compoundname>
    <title>**_TextMesh Pro User Guide_**</title>
    <briefdescription>
    </briefdescription>
    <detaileddescription>
<para><heading level="4">**Overview**</heading>
</para>
<para>This User Guide was designed to provide first time users of TextMesh Pro with a basic overview of the features and functionality of the tool.</para>
<para><heading level="4">**Installation**</heading>
</para>
<para>The TextMesh Pro UPM package is already included with the Unity Editor and as such does not require installation. TextMesh Pro &quot;TMP&quot; does however require adding resources to your project which are essential for using TextMesh Pro.</para>
<para>To import the &quot;*TMP Essential Resources*&quot;, please use the &quot;*Window -&gt; TextMeshPro -&gt; Import TMP Essential Resources*&quot; menu option. These resources will be added at the root of your project in the &quot;*TextMesh Pro*&quot; folder.</para>
<para>The TextMesh Pro package also includes additional resources and examples that will make discovering and learning about TextMesh Pro&apos;s powerful features easier. It is strongly recommended that first time users import these additional resources.</para>
<para>To import the &quot;*TMP Examples &amp; Extras*&quot;, please use the &quot;*Window -&gt; TextMeshPro -&gt; Import TMP Examples &amp; Extras*&quot; menu option. These resources will also be added in the same &quot;*TextMesh Pro*&quot; folder inside your project.</para>
<para><heading level="4">**Quick Start**</heading>
</para>
<para>There are two TextMesh Pro components available. The first TMP text component is of type &lt;TextMeshPro&gt; and designed to work with the MeshRenderer. This component is an ideal replacement for the legacy TextMesh component.</para>
<para>To add a new &lt;TextMeshPro&gt; text object, go to: “*GameObject-&gt;3D Object-&gt;TextMeshPro Text*”.</para>
<para>The second TMP text component is of type &lt;TextMeshProUGUI&gt; and designed to work with the CanvasRenderer and Canvas system. This component is an ideal replacement for the UI.Text component.</para>
<para>To add a new &lt;TextMeshProUGUI&gt; text object, go to: “*GameObject-&gt;UI-&gt;TextMeshPro Text*”.</para>
<para>You may also wish to watch this <ulink url="https://youtu.be/olnxlo-Wri4">Getting Started</ulink> short video which covers this topic.</para>
<para>We strongly recommend that you also watch the <ulink url="https://youtu.be/qzJNIGCFFtY">Font Asset Creation</ulink> video as well as the <ulink url="https://youtu.be/d2MARbDNeaA">Working with Material Presets</ulink> as these two topics is also key to working and getting the most out of TextMesh Pro.</para>
<para>As mentionned in the Installation section of this guide, it is recommended that you import the &quot;*TMP Examples &amp; Extras*&quot; and take the time to explore each of the examples as they provide a great overview of the functionality of the tool and the many text layout and <ulink url="http://digitalnativestudios.com/textmeshpro/docs/rich-text/">rich text tags</ulink> available in TextMesh Pro.</para>
<para><heading level="4">**Support &amp; API Documentation**</heading>
</para>
<para>Should you have questions or require assistance, please visit the <ulink url="https://forum.unity.com/forums/unity-ui-textmesh-pro.60/">Unity UI &amp; TextMesh Pro</ulink> section of the Unity forum as well as the <ulink url="http://digitalnativestudios.com/forum/index.php">TextMesh Pro User Forum</ulink> where you will find additional information, <ulink url="http://digitalnativestudios.com/forum/index.php?board=4.0">Video Tutorials</ulink> and <ulink url="http://digitalnativestudios.com/forum/index.php?topic=890.0">FAQ</ulink>. In the event you are unable to find the information you seek, always feel free to post on the <ulink url="https://forum.unity.com/forums/unity-ui-textmesh-pro.60/">Unity UI &amp; TextMesh Pro</ulink> section user forum.</para>
<para><ulink url="http://digitalnativestudios.com/textmeshpro/docs/">Online Documentation</ulink> is also available on TextMesh Pro including Rich Text tags, Shaders, Scripting API and more. </para>
    </detaileddescription>
  </compounddef>
</doxygen>
